<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ionic Framework</title>
    <description>The official Ionic Framework blog</description>
    <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog</link>
    <atom:link href="http://ionicframework.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Ionic Worldwide</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/community-header.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ionic Logos&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our dedicated community helps make Ionic a great hybrid mobile app development ecosystem, for which we’re very grateful. One of the most exciting things we’ve seen happening over recent months is massive growth in our international community. Meetup groups have sprung up in cities around the world, and a few dedicated devs have committed to organizing Ionic groups for entire countries. Other users have presented Ionic in cities around the world. We are humbled and delighted by their enthusiasm and by the time and energy they dedicate to spreading the word about Ionic, and we’re so thrilled to watch our international user base grow in this organic way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;We provide official support to Ionic Meetup groups, starting with cool logos and icons designed by Drifty co-founder and designer extraordinaire Ben Sperry. Groups usually then create Twitter accounts and additional social media accounts as they see fit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We help them gain a following by retweeting (and posting on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ionicframework&quot;&gt;FB&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/u/1/b/112280728135675018538/+Ionicframework/posts&quot;&gt;G+&lt;/a&gt;) event news, slides, videos, photos, and articles from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/ionicframework&quot;&gt;@ionicframework&lt;/a&gt; Twitter account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until now, prohibitive international costs and shipping time have unfortunately prevented us from providing swag, but that will be changing soon! We&amp;#39;ll keep you updated in the coming weeks about our new store. In the meantime, we&amp;#39;ve been encouraging our international Ionic groups to make their own Ionic stickers using the Logo Pack from the footer on our homepage or to order some from our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stickermule.com/user/1070630560/stickers&quot;&gt;StickerMule store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve also created an &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/present-ionic/&quot;&gt;Ionic Presentation&lt;/a&gt; that many of our meetup organizers have found useful. Most of them tweak it slightly, and many translate it, but it provides a helpful scaffolding for an introductory presentation about Ionic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re always happy to answer any questions from our Meetup groups, and we enjoy being in regular touch with them. We’ve even been known to Skype in to say hello.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a line-up of the current international Ionic groups (both countries and cities). &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:katie@drifty.com&quot;&gt;Email me&lt;/a&gt; if you’re interested in organizing a group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IonicArgentina&quot;&gt;Ionic Argentina&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Ionic Bengaluru&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IonicBE&quot;&gt;Ionic Belgium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IonicBrazil&quot;&gt;Ionic Brazil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IonicCanada&quot;&gt;Ionic Canada&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IonicChina&quot;&gt;Ionic China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IonicColombia&quot;&gt;Ionic Colombia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Ionic Czech Republic&lt;br&gt;
Ionic Delhi&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ionicgermany&quot;&gt;Ionic Germany&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Ionic India&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ionic_Ireland&quot;&gt;Ionic Ireland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Ionic Israel&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IonicItalia&quot;&gt;Ionic Italy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ionickenya&quot;&gt;Ionic Kenya&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Ionic Mumbai&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IonicNederland&quot;&gt;Ionic Netherlands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IonicParis&quot;&gt;Ionic Paris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Ionic Pakistan&lt;br&gt;
Ionic Phillippines&lt;br&gt;
Ionic Poland&lt;br&gt;
Ionic Puerto Rico&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Ionic_ru&quot;&gt;Ionic Russia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ionicspain&quot;&gt;Ionic Spain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IonicSwiss&quot;&gt;Ionic Switzerland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Ionic-Toronto/&quot;&gt;Ionic Toronto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IonicTurkey_&quot;&gt;Ionic Turkey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IonicUK&quot;&gt;Ionic UK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 14:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/ionic-worldwide/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/ionic-worldwide/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Ionic View App is Alive!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;showcase-image&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/ionic-view-app-header.gif&quot; style=&quot;margin-top:-20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re excited to announce that &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ionic-view/id849930087?mt=8&quot;&gt;Ionic View for iOS&lt;/a&gt; is now in public beta! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alpha version has been live in the App Store for a while now, and after much updating and testing, we are confident it is ready to become a useful part of your Ionic development toolchain. We want to get View out to people as soon as possible, so it may feel somewhat spare at first, but there are still many exciting features in the pipeline! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt; 

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left; margin-left: -120px; margin-right: 40px; margin-top: -12px; width: 32%;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/img/blog/songhop-preview-left.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/ionic-view-preview-left.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What is Ionic View? How Does it Fit into My Workflow?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ionic View functions like your own mobile app portfolio. It allows you to easily view, share, and test the Ionic apps you are developing across devices - your own, a client’s, or the person in the cubicle next to you (and by cubicle, we mean the pool chair at your beachside resort).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ionic View integrates with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic-cli&quot;&gt;Ionic command line&lt;/a&gt; to populate your app portfolio.  Once you’ve made sure to update your ionic-cli version to at least 1.3.2, starting and uploading an app is as easy as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;ionic start myApp
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;myApp
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;ionic upload
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll be prompted to login with your Ionic account, and upon doing so, your app will be visible in Ionic View.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How it Works&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: right; margin-right: -160px; margin-left: 40px; margin-bottom: 40px; width: 50%;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/img/blog/songhop-preview-right.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/ionic-view-preview-right.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View uses the Cordova &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cordova-plugin-inappbrowser&quot;&gt;inAppBrowser plugin&lt;/a&gt; to launch your apps in their own separate WebView, so you can preview and test them. Normally, inAppBrowser only displays web content, but we might have hacked it a little to give apps access to the Cordova API and plugins. Ionic apps are hybrid apps for a reason, and a preview is not the same without plugin support! At the moment, plugin access is restricted to a specific subset of plugins, including GeoLocation, Keyboard, StatusBar, and BarcodeScanner, and we will be testing and adding many more in the coming weeks and months.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best of all, View is an Ionic app! We hope it sets a good example of the native-quality mobile apps that are possible with Ionic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Looking Forward&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll continue to add support for new plugins as we review and test them. We’ll also be fixing some known &amp;quot;quirks&amp;quot; (you mean you didn’t want your app links to expire after five minutes of having the app open?) in the next few weeks, and we’re looking forward to adding features like auto updating and the ability to sync with a livereload server in the near future as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since View is an Ionic app, you may be wondering (or yelling), &amp;quot;Where&amp;#39;s the Android version?&amp;quot;. Have no fear, the Android version is on its way! We have been using Ionic View as a test for some of &lt;a href=&quot;https://ionic.io&quot;&gt;ionic.io&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt; services that require custom plugins, and we started with iOS first. Instead of waiting for both versions, we decided to get View out to you as quickly as possible, so you can start using and enjoying it :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ionic-view/id849930087?mt=8&quot;&gt;Click here to download Ionic View&lt;/a&gt; from Apple&amp;#39;s App Store!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a plugin in your app that’s not supported yet? Having issues with the app? Feature request? Let us know on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://forum.ionicframework.com/&quot;&gt;forum&lt;/a&gt;, hit Tim up on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/dopernicus&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or open an issue on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic-view-issues/&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 14:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/view-app-is-alive/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/view-app-is-alive/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Crosswalk comes to Ionic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;showcase-image&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/crosswalk-header.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-top:-20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ionic and Crosswalk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With our latest CLI update, we’re excited to introduce the ability to package modern rendering engines within your app
for Cordova, starting with &lt;a href=&quot;https://crosswalk-project.org/&quot;&gt;Crosswalk for Android&lt;/a&gt;. Crosswalk provides Android
developers a bundled Chrome webview for their projects, resulting in better performance and predictability!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team is passionate about making hybrid mobile development awesome, and we’re so grateful to our committed,
enthusiastic community for helping us succeed in our mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Getting Started With Crosswalk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, make sure you get the latest Ionic CLI, and then you can easily create an app, add the Android platform, and add
Crosswalk to the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;New Project&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;npm install ionic
ionic start my_app
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;my_app
ionic browser add crosswalk
ionic run android
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Previous Ionic Project&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;npm install ionic
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;existing_app
ionic browser add crosswalk
ionic run android
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Specifying a version of Crosswalk&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ionic browser list&lt;/code&gt; #Find the version of Crosswalk you want.
&lt;code&gt;ionic browser add crosswalk@10.39.235.15&lt;/code&gt;  #Install stable version 10.39.235.15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Building for separate architectures&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can either set an environment variable or pass one in-line to build separate Android APK’s for x86, ARM, and
both combined:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;BUILD_MULTIPLE_APKS=true ionic run android&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Volatility&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note that running these steps it will alter your Android project, so you’ll want to use version control to
handle changes from Crosswalk.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These commands should set you up with a custom Android build with Crosswalk. You can run the project as you normally
would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To confirm it was, in fact installed, open &lt;a href=&quot;chrome://inspect/#devices&quot;&gt;Chrome DevTools&lt;/a&gt; and confirm that it says &amp;quot;Chrome 37&amp;quot;
or greater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;d love to ask you to help out the cause by testing and giving feedback. This is your chance to help several open source projects at once: Cordova, Crosswalk, and Ionic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;10 Questions You May Ask:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve put together this Q &amp;amp; A to answer questions you might have about Crosswalk. Please don&amp;#39;t hesitate to contact us if you have questions that aren&amp;#39;t answered here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is Crosswalk?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crosswalk is an open source project that allows you to specify a version of Chrome to use as your web browser in Android.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The compiled app will have your code hosted inside of this Chrome webview.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why should I use Crosswalk?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Older versions of Android devices (4.0-4.3) use Android’s default browser, which has significantly less performance and standards compliance than modern Chrome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Crosswalk gives you a specific and more performant version of Chrome to use on all Android devices, in order to reduce fluctuations and fragmentation among devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does Crosswalk improve Cordova Android apps?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By designating a specific version of Chrome, you can skip the unexpected behavior from browsers that vary from device to device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved performance and ease of debugging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What can I expect, performance and size-wise?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In older Android Devices (4.0-4.3), you’ll see about a 10x improvement of both HTML/CSS rendering and JavaScript performance and CSS correctness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To bundle Chrome, you will see a small (~10-15MB) size increase in your Android Apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I try it out?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install -g ionic&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I report errors?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you encounter any errors, please type &lt;code&gt;ionic info&lt;/code&gt; and paste that information to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic-cli/issues&quot;&gt;Ionic CLI issues on github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What should I look for when testing?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved performance on older Android devices, with the ability to debug using Chrome DevTools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing any of the core Cordova plugins, such as Camera, GPS, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report weird behaviour while building or running the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report differences between using Crosswalk and not; for example, your splash screen no longer shows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do I debug with Crosswalk / Chrome?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fire up Chrome DevTools and go to &lt;a href=&quot;chrome://inspect/#devices&quot;&gt;Chrome Inspect Devices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the architectures for Android devices and why do they exist?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are two main Architectures for Android - x86 and ARM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The reason for the two are due to the device providers choosing to use a separate processor. With different processors, we’ll need to compile them separately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Crosswalk, you may specify that you want two separate builds for x86 / Arm to keep your build size down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you make a single build, you will have to bundle both versions of Crosswalk (x86/Arm) and have a larger build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;size (~50-60 MB).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why the switch to Gradle for Android?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Cordova Android team has decided to move away from Ant towards more of a Gradle-based build scenario.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In this upgrade, you may see alternative build messages from Gradle, instead of your normal Ant messages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;CLI Roadmap (tentative)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really important to us that we keep our users informed about what we&amp;#39;re working on. Here’s a roadmap that covers where we’ve been and where we’re going. Thanks for joining us on the journey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1.3 Milestones (1/7/2014 - 1/12/2015)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crosswalk Browser introduction &amp;amp; installation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Info command for environment-specific info.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Error reporting from CLI - helps us respond to errors faster and be proactive about errors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individual help commands - now the CLI gives more info about the individual commands &lt;code&gt;ionic help serve&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1.3.1 Milestones (1/12/2015 -1/14/2015)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specify a &lt;a href=&quot;https://download.01.org/crosswalk/releases/crosswalk/android/stable/&quot;&gt;version of Crosswalk&lt;/a&gt; to use - &lt;code&gt;ionic browser add crosswalk@10.39.235.15&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See all the browsers available to install - &lt;code&gt;ionic browser list&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;em&gt;NOTE: Only stable releases are allowed for now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug related to &lt;code&gt;ionic upload&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caching the Crosswalk downloads - once you’ve installed a version in a project, running &lt;code&gt;ionic browser add crosswalk&lt;/code&gt; will not re-download the webviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1.3.2 Milestones (1/14/2015 - 1/23/2015)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick fix for the &lt;code&gt;ionic upload&lt;/code&gt; command - fixed an issue with the cookies from the request.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1.3.3 Milestones (1/23/2015 - onward)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a release option that removes unused files and minifies/uglifies to give you smaller builds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the ability to specify Beta/Canary builds of Crosswalk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a way to release Android builds post 4.4 without Crosswalk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make using the CLI easier with tab complete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic-cli#crosswalk-for-android&quot;&gt;Crosswalk Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 02:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/crosswalk-comes-to-ionic/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/crosswalk-comes-to-ionic/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minifying Your App's Source Code</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post by &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.nraboy.com/&quot;&gt;Nic Raboy&lt;/a&gt;, an application developer with a strong background in
Android, AngularJS, Ionic, Java, SQL, and Unity3D. Nic writes often about Ionic and how to build great hybrid apps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, I wrote about the importance of uglifying your Apache Cordova source code. If you read my &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.nraboy.com/2014/11/extract-android-apk-view-source-code/&quot;&gt;previous
post&lt;/a&gt; you&amp;#39;ll know that hybrid applications are
incredibly easy to decompile, so uglifying your code creates additional difficulty for any malicious user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.nraboy.com/2014/12/use-grunt-lint-uglify-javascript-project/&quot;&gt;generic post&lt;/a&gt; about how to use
the Grunt task runner to lint and uglify your code. However, using Grunt isn&amp;#39;t the most ideal solution when it comes to
linting your Apache Cordova project for errors and uglifying your code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this guide, we&amp;#39;re going to see how to efficiently lint and minify your Apache Cordova project before building. The
same information can be applied against &lt;a href=&quot;http://phonegap.com/&quot;&gt;Phonegap&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ionicframework.com&quot;&gt;Ionic
Framework&lt;/a&gt; projects, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s start by creating a fresh Apache Cordova Android and iOS project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;cordova create TestProject com.nraboy.testproject TestProject
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;TestProject
cordova platform add android
cordova platform add ios
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that if you&amp;#39;re not using a Mac, you cannot add or build for the iOS platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tutorial is going to be broken into two parts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linting the project for JavaScript errors&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uglifying the code for obfuscation purposes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#39;ve run these steps, your project will be in much better shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Linting the project for JavaScript errors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my subscribers recommended I check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/cordova-linter&quot;&gt;Cordova Linter&lt;/a&gt; for this
task. I checked it out and couldn&amp;#39;t figure out how to get it to work. It kept saying my project had no errors, when I
know it did. The package had no documentation to prove its process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is when I decided to create my own Apache Cordova hook. If you&amp;#39;ve read my &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.nraboy.com/2015/01/hooks-apache-cordova-mobile-applications/&quot;&gt;previous
post&lt;/a&gt; regarding hooks, you should have a
general idea of what we&amp;#39;re going to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;hooks/before_prepare/02_jshint.js&lt;/code&gt;, and make sure to give it execute permissions if you&amp;#39;re using Linux or Mac.
Based on the file title, you can probably guess we&amp;#39;re going to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://jshint.com/docs/&quot;&gt;JSHint&lt;/a&gt; for linting. Open
&lt;code&gt;02_jshint.js&lt;/code&gt;, and add the following code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;/usr/bin/env node&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;fs&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;fs&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;path&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;jshint&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;jshint&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;JSHINT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;async&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;async&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;foldersToProcess&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;js&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;];&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;foldersToProcess&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;forEach&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;folder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;processFiles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;www/&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;folder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;processFiles&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;dir&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;callback&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;errorCount&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;fs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;readdir&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;dir&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;list&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;processFiles err: &amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;async&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;eachSeries&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;list&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;innercallback&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;dir&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;/&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;fs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;stat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;stat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;stat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;isDirectory&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;())&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;extname&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;===&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;.js&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;lintFile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;hasError&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                            &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;hasError&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                                &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;errorCount&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
                            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;innercallback&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;innercallback&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;innercallback&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;errorCount&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;process&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;exit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;lintFile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;callback&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Linting &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;fs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;readFile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Error: &amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;jshint&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;toString&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()))&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;File &amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39; has no errors.&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;-----------------------------------------&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;callback&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Errors in file &amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;out&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;jshint&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;errors&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;errors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;errors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;length&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;errors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;line&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;:&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;errors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;character&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39; -&amp;gt; &amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;errors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;reason&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39; -&amp;gt; &amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;errors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;j&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;evidence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;-----------------------------------------&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;callback&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kc&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above script will look at only the &lt;code&gt;www/js&lt;/code&gt; directory, but feel free to add further directories. All
files in the directory will be looped through, and if they are JavaScript, the file will be fed into JSHint. If any
files contain errors, they will be presented to the screen, and then the script will stop all further processes. This
means that if you execute the script with &lt;code&gt;cordova build [platform]&lt;/code&gt;, the application will not continue to build if errors are found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;02_jshint.js&lt;/code&gt; requires two NodeJS libraries in order to function. They can be installed like this from the root of
your project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;npm install jshint
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;npm install async
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Uglifying the code for obfuscation purposes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my other subscribers recommended I check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/cordova-uglify&quot;&gt;Cordova Uglify&lt;/a&gt; for
the obfuscation process. Unlike Cordova Linter, this NPM package actually worked as advertised. From the root of your
Apache Cordova project, run the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;npm install cordova-uglify
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the installation completes, you should find that &lt;code&gt;hooks/after_prepare/uglify.js&lt;/code&gt; was created. If you&amp;#39;re on Linux
or Mac, you&amp;#39;ll need to give it execute permissions; otherwise, it won&amp;#39;t be picked up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can test that this script worked by running &lt;code&gt;cordova prepare&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;cordova build [platform]&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, Apache Cordova does not check your code for errors when building. This means you won&amp;#39;t know if errors
exist in your code until you run your application. Linting your code can save you a lot of stress when it comes to
finding errors caused by typos or missing/extra brackets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your hard work is very easy to decompile by default, so it is a good idea to obfuscate your code by means of
uglification before you release your application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two videos for this article can be seen below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;510&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/qQiYE6x7cFk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;510&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/hoy3MESySWQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 02:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/minifying-your-source-code/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/minifying-your-source-code/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Navigating the Changes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Before releasing Beta 14, we took some time to gather feedback from the Ionic community about how navigation UI should
behave: not just how it should be animated, but how
everything comes together in an app. In Beta 14, we made some major changes to the navigation structure and elements
that follow some already well-established patterns
that can be found in apps across all platforms. We feel these updates will smooth the process of building UI navigation
for your app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Nav buttons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Beta 14, we introduced a new navbar inheritance structure. Any collection of elements in &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ion-nav-buttons&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; or
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ion-nav-title&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; will replace what’s in the header by default or from the main top-level view (likely your index.html
file).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many cases, you’ll want just one &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ion-nav-bar&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, and then you’ll add the appropriate buttons for that page to the
page’s template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the example below, we define a nav-bar, with a button on the right, and then make a view that has a button on the
left. When that view renders, it will contain both buttons, so the view will inherit any button that is already in the
nav-bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your typical structure will be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- index.html --&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ion-nav-bar&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ion-nav-buttons&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;side=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;secondary&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;button&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;button&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;ng-click=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;doSomething()&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      Add
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ion-nav-buttons&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ion-nav-bar&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ion-nav-view&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ion-nav-view&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- some view template --&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ion-view&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ion-nav-buttons&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;side=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;primary&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;button&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;button&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;ng-click=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;doSomethingElse()&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      More
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ion-nav-buttons&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ion-content&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    Some super content here!
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ion-content&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ion-view&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Navigation base&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we released Beta 14, we revisited the way we felt navigation UI should behave. Components like our &lt;code&gt;ion-tab&lt;/code&gt; and
our &lt;code&gt;ion-side-menus&lt;/code&gt; now have a lot more purpose behind them. Like their native counterparts, these components have
become a base for navigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at our side-menus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ion-side-menus&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;enable-menu-with-back-views=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;false&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ion-side-menu-content&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ion-nav-bar&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;bar-positive&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ion-nav-back-button&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ion-nav-back-button&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ion-nav-buttons&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;side=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;button&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;button button-icon button-clear ion-navicon&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;menu-toggle=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ion-nav-buttons&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ion-nav-bar&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ion-nav-view&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;name=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;menuContent&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ion-nav-view&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ion-side-menu-content&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ion-side-menu&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;side=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ion-content&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ul&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;list&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;#/event/check-in&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;item&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;menu-close&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Check-in&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;#/event/attendees&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;item&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;menu-close&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Attendees&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ion-content&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ion-side-menu&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ion-side-menus&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that left side-menu, you probably have a list of links to other pages in your app, while in the side-menu-content,
you’d have a nav-view to render these pages. In Beta 14, those links in the side-menu now trigger a change in the
navigation stack. The view gets treated as a navigation root and has animation only on the child views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, you may not be able to use side-menus haphazardly in any view. The use of a menu should be to create a base
of navigation, through which views will transition. For a more contextual menu, developers should consider components
like &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/ionic/pen/GpCst&quot;&gt;popover&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/ionic/pen/gblny&quot;&gt;modal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Menu Toggle Visibility&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our navigation research, we discovered that existing native SDKs that have a similar side-menu component and
navigation stack automatically hide the menu toggle (hamburger) icon-button icon on child pages; it’s only visible on
root level pages. We agree with this UX approach and have made it possible using &lt;code&gt;enable-menu-with-back-views=&amp;quot;false&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;
on the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ion-side-menus&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/docs/nightly/api/directive/ionSideMenus/&quot;&gt;ionSideMenus Docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;View LifeCycle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to improve performance, we&amp;#39;ve improved Ionic&amp;#39;s ability to cache view elements and scope data. Once a controller
is initialized, it may persist throughout the app’s life; it’s just hidden and removed from the watch cycle. Since we
aren’t rebuilding scope, we’ve added events for which we should listen when entering the watch cycle again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;table&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ionicView.loaded&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The view has loaded. This event only happens once per view being created and added to the DOM. If a view leaves but
is cached, then this event will not fire again on a subsequent viewing. The loaded event is good place to put your setup
code for the view; however, it is not the recommended event to listen to when a view becomes active.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ionicView.enter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The view has fully entered and is now the active view.
This event will fire, whether it was the first load or a cached view.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ionicView.leave&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The view has finished leaving and is no longer the
active view. This event will fire, whether it is cached or destroyed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ionicView.beforeEnter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The view is about to enter and become the active view.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ionicView.beforeLeave&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The view is about to leave and no longer be the active view.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ionicView.afterEnter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The view has fully entered and is now the active view.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ionicView.afterLeave&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The view has finished leaving and is no longer the active view.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ionicView.unloaded&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The view&#39;s controller has been destroyed, and its element has been
removed from the DOM.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of using these events would be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$scope&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$on&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;$ionicView.afterEnter&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// Any thing you can think of&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Parting Words&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these updates, Ionic now has a more complete structure for navigation and view management. Check out the docs for
more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/docs/api/directive/ionNavView/&quot;&gt;ionNavView&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/docs/api/directive/ionNavButtons/&quot;&gt;ionNavButtons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/docs/api/directive/ionSideMenus/&quot;&gt;ionSideMenus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/docs/api/directive/ionTabs/&quot;&gt;ionTabs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 02:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/navigating-the-changes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/navigating-the-changes/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Automating Icons and Splash Screens</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;showcase-image&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/splash-header.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-top:-20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the first thing users see when they download your app? What about after they install it and start the app?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An app icon and splash screen (launch image) are important parts of any app, yet making them used to be incredibly
tedious. You needed numerous icons for iOS and Android, and then you had to deal with splash screens and all their
different sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To save you the stress of dealing with all that, we’ve made it possible for you to generate app icons and splash screens
via the Ionic CLI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Generate those Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new CLI, all you need is a resource directory and two images. These images can be  &lt;code&gt;.png&lt;/code&gt; files, Photoshop
&lt;code&gt;.psd&lt;/code&gt; files, or Illustrator &lt;code&gt;.ai&lt;/code&gt; files, named icon.png (for example) and splash.png. With the images in a resources
directory, &lt;code&gt;./resources&lt;/code&gt;, the &lt;code&gt;ionic resources&lt;/code&gt; command will generate the icons and splash screen images for  each
platform setup in the project, sending them to Ionic&amp;#39;s image resizing and cropping server, so you don&amp;#39;t have to  install
extra dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;ionic resources
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the images are generated, the CLI will update the &lt;code&gt;config.xml&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://cordova.apache.org/docs/en/4.0.0/config_ref_images.md.html#Icons%20and%20Splash%20Screens&quot;&gt;include the icons and splash
screens&lt;/a&gt;, so they
will be transferred over in Cordova&amp;#39;s build process. NOTE: This process requires Cordova CLI version 3.6 or higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you only need to update one of the resources, or you only want to generate icons and not both, the &lt;code&gt;ionic resources&lt;/code&gt;
command has two flags that allow you to target each asset, instead of generating both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;ionic resources --icon
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;ionic resources --splash
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Image Sizes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to be able to crop and resize images to fit the various needs of each platform, icons and splash screen images
should meet a minimum size requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The icon image&amp;#39;s minimum dimensions should be 192x192 px and should have no rounded corners. Note that each platform
will apply its own mask and effects to the icons. For example, iOS will automatically apply its custom rounded corners,
so the source file should not already come with rounded corners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Splash screen dimensions vary for each platform, device, and orientation, so a square source image is required to
generate each of the various screen sizes. The source image&amp;#39;s minimum dimensions should be 2208x2208 px, and the artwork
should be centered within the square, because each generated image will be center cropped into landscape and portrait
images.
The splash screen&amp;#39;s artwork should roughly fit within a center square (1200x1200 px). This
&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.ionicframework.com/resources/splash.psd&quot;&gt;template&lt;/a&gt; provides the recommended size and guidelines about
artwork&amp;#39;s safe zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Platform Specifics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want different icons for the iOS and Android versions of your app? No problem; we’ve got that covered, too. To use
different source images for individual platforms, place the source image in the respective platform&amp;#39;s directory. To use
a different icon for Android, the image should follow this path: &lt;code&gt;resources/android/icon.png&lt;/code&gt;, and the image for iOS
should use this path: &lt;code&gt;resources/ios/icon.png&lt;/code&gt;. This way, you can have an iOS icon with native rounded corners and an
Android icon with a transparent background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just one more way Ionic aims to make developers’ lives easier, not to mention more fun. Update your CLI and try
out the resource generator today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;npm install -g ionic
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What&amp;#39;s Next&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned in our Beta 14 blog post, we&amp;#39;ve been working on adding Crosswalk integration for Android into our CLI.
Josh has been hard at work on this, and it will be landing in the CLI as a beta feature soon. Keep an eye on the CLI!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic-cli#icon-and-splash-screen-image-generation&quot;&gt;Ionic-CLI Resource Generator Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cordova.apache.org/docs/en/edge/config_ref_images.md.html#Icons%20and%20Splash%20Screens&quot;&gt;Cordova Icons and Splash Screens
Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.ionicframework.com/resources/splash.psd&quot;&gt;Splash screen photoshop template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 02:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/automating-icons-and-splash-screens/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/automating-icons-and-splash-screens/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fast code deployments with Docker</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are huge fans of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; here at Ionic. Docker keeps our code and its dependencies together and lets us more fully utilize our computing resources for products like &lt;a href=&quot;https://creator.ionic.io/&quot;&gt;Ionic Creator&lt;/a&gt; and the upcoming &lt;a href=&quot;https://ionic.io/&quot;&gt;Ionic.io&lt;/a&gt; services. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One challenge we faced with Docker, though, was that any time we made even the smallest change to our code, we had to go through the process of building a new container, pulling it down to our servers, and replacing the running version.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We store all of our code in GitHub, use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker Registry&lt;/a&gt; to automatically build and store our containers, and use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ansible.com/&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt; to script the management and deployment of our containers to our servers. Even with a fully automated process, deploying that one small change could take us 20 minutes or more. After some brainstorming, we realized there is a better way for us to utilize Docker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the initial container build, 99% of our changes are purely code. We aren&amp;#39;t adding any new dependencies or changing any of the requirements for running the code. Docker is really just a way to encapsulate the infrastructure required to run our code in a self-contained package. Because 99% of our changes are to code, not infrastructure, we realized we didn’t need to go through the effort to rebuild the infrastructure on every change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The killer Docker feature that lets us solve this problem is &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/userguide/dockervolumes/&quot;&gt;volumes&lt;/a&gt;. In the first iterations of our Docker files, our code was pulled from GitHub and built directly into the container. Now, we deliberately leave the code out of the container and instead load it through a host volume on container start. When we want to do a new deploy, Ansible pulls down our master branch from GitHub into an app directory on our servers. Then it checks to make sure that the associated container is running, and if it&amp;#39;s not, it will start the container and map the app code into the container.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other component that makes this work for us is that most of our apps are Python (Django), and we serve them with uWSGI inside the Docker container. uWSGI has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://uwsgi-docs.readthedocs.org/en/latest/Options.html#touch-reload&quot;&gt;touch reload&lt;/a&gt; feature that watches a specified file and reloads the uWSGI server when the file is touched. After Ansible has pulled our changes from GitHub, we have Ansible touch the uwsgi.ini file, which triggers uWSGI to reload inside the running container. Just like that, we’re running the updated version of our code!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this means, in brief, is that we took our deployments from a 20+ minute process that looked like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit and push to GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Registry pulls the changes and builds a new container.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ansible connects to our servers and pulls the new container.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ansible finds any running instances of the old container and stops them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ansible starts new instances of the container.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to this approximately 10 second process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit and push to GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ansible connects to our servers, pulls latest master from GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ansible touches the app&amp;#39;s uwsgi.ini file to trigger UWSGI to reload.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Breaking it down&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Supervisor / uWSGI&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are using &lt;a href=&quot;http://supervisord.org/&quot;&gt;Supervisor&lt;/a&gt; inside the Docker container to start the processes run by the container. Our supervisord.conf looks like the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ini&quot; data-lang=&quot;ini&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;[supervisord]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;nodaemon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;[program:uwsgi]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;command&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;/usr/local/bin/uwsgi --touch-reload=/path/to/code/in/container/uwsgi.ini --ini /path/to/code/in/container/uwsgi.ini&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are using the uwsgi.ini file as the trigger file via the &lt;a href=&quot;http://uwsgi-docs.readthedocs.org/en/latest/Options.html#touch-reload&quot;&gt;--touch-reload&lt;/a&gt; flag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Docker&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we start our container, we add a host volume that contains the code for our app. That host volume is mapped to an app path in the container from which uWSGI will load the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;docker run -d -P -v /path/to/code/on/host:/path/to/code/in/container --name&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;container_name driftyco/testapp
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ansible&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ansible is in charge of cloning the application code from GitHub into our host&amp;#39;s app directory, ensuring that the Docker container is running and touching the uWSGI touch-reload trigger file. We have created playbooks to direct the deployment of each of our services, so deploying is just a matter of running the right one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a quick code deploy, we run a playbook that contains these tasks and takes only a few seconds to run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;set_fact&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;host_volume=&amp;quot;/path/to/code/on/host&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;Git pull the latest code&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;git&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;repo=git@github.com:{{ org }}/{{ container }}.git&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;dest={{ host_volume }}&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;accept_hostkey=yes&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;force=yes&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;Gracefully reload uwsgi&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;path={{ touch_file }} state=touch&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we need to restart the entire container or update system packages, we can do a container deploy, which takes a few minutes, with these tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;Add app dir if it doesn&amp;#39;t yet exist&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;path={{ host_volume }} owner=nobody group=docker recurse=yes state=directory&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;sudo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;yes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;Pull Docker image&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;command&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;{{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;item&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;}}&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;ignore_errors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;yes&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;with_items&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;docker pull {{ org }}/{{ container }}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;docker stop {{ container }}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;docker rm {{ container }}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;Run Docker image with app volumes&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;command&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;docker run -d -P -v {{ host_volume }}:{{ container_volume }} --name={{ container }} {{ extra_params }} {{ org }}/{{ container }}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a full deploy, we run both playbooks together in sequence; it’s that simple. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Docker is primarily a way to encapsulate infrastructure into a self-contained, deployable package, there is often no need to rebuild the entire container just to deploy a couple code changes. By utilizing volumes in Docker, we remove the code from the container, enabling code to be updated independently of the container that runs it. Finally, we can use the UWSGI touch reload feature to restart UWSGI in the container and load the updated code from the volume. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 14:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/docker-hot-code-deploys/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/docker-hot-code-deploys/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ionic: Year One in Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;showcase-image&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/ionic-1year-header.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-top:-20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014 is coming to a close, and what a year it has been!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s hard to believe, but Ionic is only one year old. When we launched at the end of 2013, we had no clue how voracious developers&amp;#39; appetites for building hybrid apps would be. We thought we&amp;#39;d have some early adopters trying out the framework, but we certainly did not expect the massive adoption of Ionic that we&amp;#39;ve seen in just one year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our conclusion from 2014 is that hybrid is not only here to stay, but has become a &lt;em&gt;much better&lt;/em&gt; solution than native for many app developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;By the Numbers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014 alone, Ionic became one of the &lt;strong&gt;top 50&lt;/strong&gt; most popular open source projects in the world, with over &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic&quot;&gt;12,000 stars&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over &lt;strong&gt;320,000&lt;/strong&gt; apps have been created this year, and some &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/blog/built-with-ionic-sworkit/&quot;&gt;particularly impressive&lt;/a&gt; ones were featured by both Apple and Google in their respective app stores. Ionic is being used by freelancers, startups, and Fortune 50 companies alike, and in more countries than we can even count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/by-the-numbers-map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ionic numbers&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every month, over 50,000 new apps are created, and over half a million unique developers visit the Ionic website for documentation and to read our blog posts about hybrid apps and the broader mobile dev ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;http://forum.ionicframework.com/&quot;&gt;forum&lt;/a&gt; has seen over 45,000 posts this year, reaching over 100,000 unique developers a month. It&amp;#39;s turning into a great place to get help and collaborate with the Ionic community, and even to find interesting work available to Ionic developers around the world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=ionic&quot;&gt;#ionic&lt;/a&gt; IRC room on Freenode has nearly 100 active users at any given time! Having an official single-hash room on Freenode has been a personal dream of mine ever since I started using IRC 15 years ago, so I am thrilled to see our IRC room being so widely utilized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Partnerships&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also proud that Ionic has been integrated into such great tools as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jetbrains.com/webstorm/whatsnew/&quot;&gt;Web Storm&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://tools.jboss.org/documentation/whatsnew/jbosstools/4.2.0.CR1.html#ionic&quot;&gt;JBoss&lt;/a&gt;. There are a few bigger tools integrating Ionic that we can&amp;#39;t talk about just yet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Heroku team has also been good to Ionic, creating a &lt;a href=&quot;http://engineering.heroku.com/blogs/2014-10-02-heroku-mobile-app-template&quot;&gt;Mobile Template&lt;/a&gt; that can be deployed to Heroku with one click and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://heroku.github.io/nibs/&quot;&gt;full demo&lt;/a&gt; app using Ionic, Heroku, and the Salesforce1 platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/firebase/firebase-angular-starter-pack&quot;&gt;Ionic starter templates&lt;/a&gt; from the Firebase team, and Firebase is quickly becoming the preferred real-time backend solution for Ionic apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also incredibly thankful for the support from the AngularJS team and community. We look forward to talking more about and incorporating
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/angular/material&quot;&gt;ngMaterial&lt;/a&gt;, our collaboration with the AngularJS team to implement material design in Angular (and eventually the core Android look and feel for Ionic apps)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Bloggers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ionic wouldn&amp;#39;t be where it is today without the amazing content written by hybrid, AngularJS, and mobile dev bloggers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re grateful to have had some great bloggers like &lt;a href=&quot;http://devgirl.org/&quot;&gt;Holly Schinsky&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.raymondcamden.com/&quot;&gt;Raymond Camden&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://coenraets.org/blog/2014/10/ionic-tutorial-and-sample-application/&quot;&gt;Christophe Coenrates&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nraboy.com/&quot;&gt;Nic Raboy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mcgivery.com/&quot;&gt;Andrew McGivery&lt;/a&gt; write incredible and educational posts on Ionic that the Ionic community loves reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, there are several books being written about Ionic right now from major tech publishers. One that we can talk about now is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.manning.com/wilken/&quot;&gt;Ionic in Action&lt;/a&gt; from Manning Publications. The book is &lt;a href=&quot;http://myemail.constantcontact.com/Dec-17--Apache-Cordova-in-Action.html?soid=1101335703814&amp;amp;aid=2sPCIgmMgxs&quot;&gt;on sale&lt;/a&gt; today, along with Raymond&amp;#39;s wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.manning.com/camden/&quot;&gt;Cordova in Action&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/smichelotti&quot;&gt;Steve Michelotti&lt;/a&gt; created a wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pluralsight.com/courses/description/building-mobile-apps-ionic-framework-angularjs&quot;&gt;Pluralsight Course&lt;/a&gt; on Ionic, with over three hours of video content. It&amp;#39;s very popular course on the site and a great resource for learning more about Ionic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who has written about Ionic; please get in touch if you&amp;#39;d like to help create more content to post on the Ionic blog!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Taking over the world&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ionic developers have given hundreds of talks at meetups and conferences this year and have written blog posts, demos, and tutorials. On top of that, we&amp;#39;re starting to see a multi-national band of Ionic user groups forming around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/ionic-community-logos.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ionic Logos&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are official Ionic meetup groups started by Ionic community members that we help to get up and running. If you&amp;#39;d like to start your own official Ionic meetup group, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:katie@drifty.com&quot;&gt;let us know!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Startups&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many startups are using Ionic to build their apps and reach the growing hybrid developer community. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/itsmayho&quot;&gt;Mehul&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gdi2290&quot;&gt;Patrick&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://keychainlogistics.com/&quot;&gt;Keychain Logistics&lt;/a&gt; were our earliest fans, switching from native iOS and Android apps to a single Ionic app for both platforms. &lt;a href=&quot;http://sworkit.com/&quot;&gt;Sworkit&lt;/a&gt; is a top health and fitness app with millions of users that has been able to rapidly iterate with Ionic. &lt;a href=&quot;https://mallzee.com/&quot;&gt;Mallzee&lt;/a&gt;, a top shopping app, started in the UK and recently launched in the U.S. &lt;a href=&quot;http://habitrpg.com/&quot;&gt;HabitRPG&lt;/a&gt; is an incredibly popular game built with Ionic that makes building healthy habits fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://apppresser.com/&quot;&gt;Appresser&lt;/a&gt; generates Ionic apps from WordPress sites. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.femtoduino.com/&quot;&gt;Femtoduino&lt;/a&gt; is creating tiny Arduino clones with companion apps built on Ionic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Auth0 wrote a great post on &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/blog/authentication-in-ionic/&quot;&gt;using their auth system with Ionic&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://rethinkdb.com/&quot;&gt;RethinkDB&lt;/a&gt; team built &lt;a href=&quot;http://rethinkdb.com/blog/beerthink/&quot;&gt;BeerThink&lt;/a&gt;, an infinite scrolling app with Ionic, Node.js, and RethinkDB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also happy to have many &lt;a href=&quot;http://ycombinator.com/&quot;&gt;Y Combinator&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://techstars.com/&quot;&gt;TechStars&lt;/a&gt; startups using Ionic. Startups are clearly recognizing the major economic benefits of going hybrid, and we know this is only going to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We quietly released a very early preview of what we are calling &lt;a href=&quot;http://ions.ionic.io/&quot;&gt;Ionic Ions&lt;/a&gt;, a set of add-ons and widgets that give your Ionic apps special powers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/ions-logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ions&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we&amp;#39;ve grown Ionic, we&amp;#39;ve created add-ons like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic-ion-header-shrink&quot;&gt;Shrinking Headers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic-ion-frost&quot;&gt;Frosted Glass&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic-ion-tinder-cards&quot;&gt;Tinder-Style Swipe Cards&lt;/a&gt;. We realized early on that these add-ons don&amp;#39;t make sense as part of the core Ionic project, but they&amp;#39;re an integral part of the larger Ionic ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to encourage Ionic developers to create reusable widgets, and we&amp;#39;ll make it easy to submit them to the official Ions repository soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can test out Ions today by using the &lt;code&gt;$ ionic add ION&lt;/code&gt; command, and we will have a lot more info about this in the near future!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ionicons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project started in late 2013 but is worth mentioning here: Our official &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicons.com/&quot;&gt;icon pack&lt;/a&gt;, including over 700 totally free and open source icons, was released last year. The project has over 5,000 stars on GitHub and has quickly become one of the most popular icon packs on the web! Version 2.0 was released last week and has lots of new icons (Note: Ionic uses 1.5.2 right now, so make sure to use the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicons.com/1.5.2/&quot;&gt;older docs&lt;/a&gt; until we upgrade).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/year-ionicons1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ionicons&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;ngCordova&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ngcordova.com/&quot;&gt;ngCordova&lt;/a&gt;, our project to wrap the myriad Cordova plugins with clean and consistent AngularJS APIs, was launched mid-2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/year-ngcordova.png&quot; alt=&quot;ngCordova&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea for ngCordova was proposed by a community member, and the first version was built over a weekend. We&amp;#39;ve had the incredible fortune of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/paolobernasconi&quot;&gt;Paolo Bernasconi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s great leadership on the project, taking it from a humble 13 plugins to over 55 plugins today! Paolo is one of our biggest heroes, and we are so thankful to have him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much to our surprise, the project took off, with over 1,300 stars, 57 contributors, and 250 pull requests submitted in the last several months. Expect ngCordova to be an increasingly large part of Ionic going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ionic Lab&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just last week, &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/ionic-lab/&quot;&gt;we released&lt;/a&gt; the first version of Ionic Lab, an extension to our command line utilities that makes the development and debugging process easier, faster, and more fun. Ionic Lab is an AngularJS app that runs locally to help you test and develop your Ionic apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/year-lab.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ionic Lab&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One useful feature is built-in support for our platform-specific styles and features. Develop the iOS and Android versions of your app side-by-side, without having to fire up an emulator or test on the device:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ionic Lab appears to have struck a chord with the developer community, and our minds are racing about its massive potential. We can&amp;#39;t talk about our specific plans just yet, but expect Ionic Lab to expand greatly in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ionic Creator and Theme Tool&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We announced the beta for &lt;a href=&quot;https://creator.ionic.io/&quot;&gt;Ionic Creator&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, with the goal of making it easier and faster to build and export Ionic prototypes. The reception was incredible, with over 25,000 developers signing up for the beta in the month or so after our announcement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/creator/creator-preview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ionic Creator&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are proud to announce that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://creator.ionic.io/&quot;&gt;Creator&lt;/a&gt; is now publicly available, though this is just the first iteration of the tool. We hope you&amp;#39;ll give it a try and let us know what you think about it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/paolobernasconi&quot;&gt;Paolo&lt;/a&gt; created and released the first version of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionic-theme-editor.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;Ionic Tailor&lt;/a&gt;, a simple theme generator tool for Ionic styles. It&amp;#39;s a great way to customize the default look and feel of Ionic to fit your brand! Expect a lot more out of this tool in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ionic 1.0&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next big release of Ionic is slated for early 2015, and we&amp;#39;re going for 1.0! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/the-final-beta/&quot;&gt;Beta 14&lt;/a&gt; this week, we&amp;#39;ve made Ionic the fastest and most feature-complete hybrid development framework around. Drawing on lessons learned from building native apps, we&amp;#39;ve added features like view caching, dynamic platform transitions, and UI adaptation, along with hundreds of bug fixes and improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be our last beta release. After the holidays, we will be releasing rc0 and moving toward 1.0 in early 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ionic.io&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Ionic developers often lament the lack of hybrid app services available to them. Unfortunately, most mobile development services target native developers, and often &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; native iOS developers. Mobile service providers have been oblivious to hybrid development, and we want to change that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launching in 2015, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ionic.io/&quot;&gt;Ionic.io&lt;/a&gt; will offer powerful mobile services and tools focused on Ionic apps and hybrid apps in general. Track usage and analytics, understand the impact of UI decisions, send intelligent push notifications, and update your app without resubmitting to the App Store. Ionic.io will help you do all of this and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be our first commercial offering. Make sure to &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionic.io/&quot;&gt;sign up for the beta&lt;/a&gt; to get updates on the release!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The road ahead&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We owe our biggest debt of gratitude to you, the Ionic community. Thank you for everything you do to contribute to and support Ionic. You have helped build a fantastic product and have made it successful beyond anyone&amp;#39;s wildest dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015, we will need you more than ever, as we move beyond our humble beginnings as an AngularJS framework into a full-fledged mobile development platform. We want Ionic to be &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; way mobile apps are built in the future, and we can&amp;#39;t do that without you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So stay tuned for many more Ionic updates in 2015 as the project matures and moves up the mobile dev stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From all of us on the Ionic Team, we wish you a very happy holidays and a wonderful new year! Go kick some apps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adam, Tim, Katie, Ben, Andrew, Joel, Mike, Peter, Jamie, Perry, Melissa, Brody, Max, Drew, and Josh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/ionic-one-year-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/ionic-one-year-review/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Beta 14: The Final Beta</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;showcase-image&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/b14-header.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-top:-20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we&amp;#39;re thrilled to announce Ionic 1.0 Beta 14, The Last of the Betas! Beta 14 takes Ionic beyond its birth as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/blog/beyond-framework/&quot;&gt;framework&lt;/a&gt; to its current state as a complete suite of solutions for hybrid mobile app development. After we released Beta 13, our team examined our tools and services and analyzed areas where we could make improvements for hybrid app development. The desire to meet the needs of our developers in the best way possible is the driving force behind every decision we make about Ionic. For this release, we focused on performance boosts, caching, view transitions, and platform-specific changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Update to Angular 1.3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest updates we&amp;#39;ve made in this release is that we&amp;#39;ve migrated Ionic&amp;#39;s core to work with &lt;a href=&quot;http://angularjs.blogspot.com/2014/10/angularjs-130-superluminal-nudge.html&quot;&gt;Angular 1.3&lt;/a&gt;, which offers supercharged performance and slick new features. Take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.angularjs.org/guide/migration#migrating-from-1-2-to-1-3&quot;&gt;Angular&amp;#39;s Migration Page&lt;/a&gt; to get familiar with any changes that apply to your app!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Caching, Transitions, and Platform Configuration, Oh My!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Caching&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One huge performance boost we&amp;#39;ve added is the caching of views. It used to be that views and their scopes were destroyed as soon as the user navigated away from them. While this is the normal behavior for views in Angular, it&amp;#39;s also a big hit for performance and perceived speed to have the same elements and data reloaded on every viewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, when the user transitions away from a view, the scope is disconnected, rather than destroyed, and the view is kept in the DOM (don&amp;#39;t worry; it&amp;#39;s hidden and not being rendered, so it won&amp;#39;t impact performance). This allows us to essentially cache the view and reconnect the scopes, instead of rebuilding them. This means all that data crunching to get a controller spun up only needs to happen once. The controller and its data can stay in memory and listen for events, just like native apps. By default, Ionic will cache only 10 views, but this is all &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/docs/api/directive/ionNavView/&quot;&gt;highly configurable&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to hold scroll position as a user navigates forward and back is great for user interaction. For example, if the user scrolls down a large list on View A, then navigates to a detail page in View B, then navigates back to View A, it&amp;#39;ll still be at the same scroll position (without any data reloading or skippy scrolling).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Ionic&amp;#39;s Got Some New Moves&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you follow any of the Ionic devs on Twitter, you&amp;#39;ve probably seen some hints about what we&amp;#39;ve been working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;showcase-image&quot; style=&quot;display: block; margin: auto;&quot; src=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/B1DcthWCYAA45I1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent a lot of time analyzing both iOS and Android animations to figure out exactly how they work. In iOS, there are about 20 different things happening all at once. New nav-bar buttons fade in, and old buttons fade out. Old titles slide to the back button text, and new titles slide in. The old view slides away, and the new view slides in, all while an overlay fades in. And that&amp;#39;s just for the transition to a new view! Going back is a slightly different variation of this. We also spent a lot of time looking at how views transition in Android 5.0, paying special attention to the ways in which transitions are done with tabs in Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We encourage Ionic app developers to embrace platform specific changes, so users feel right at home using interactions and layouts with which they&amp;#39;re familiar. For example, iOS apps have center-aligned titles and header buttons on the left and right, while Android apps have left-aligned titles and header buttons on the right. In Beta 14, we&amp;#39;ve added these as defaults, so  platform-specific UI changes happen &lt;em&gt;automatically&lt;/em&gt;, but they can all still be configured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was clear to us that we needed to rethink our transition system and how we were handling views. Simple CSS transitions weren&amp;#39;t cutting it, especially because we wanted a transition to also be controlled with user-interaction (think swipe-to-go-back). This realization drove us to create our new view transition and caching system and to structure the core so it is easily configurable. With this new setup, we&amp;#39;ll begin working on a new animations pack to provide even more compelling animations. Expect even more to come!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Configure All The Things&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also created the  &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/docs/api/provider/$ionicConfigProvider/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ionicConfigProvider&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a powerful feature that allows you to customize nearly every aspect of your app, from where the title aligns in the nav-bar to the style of animations used for transitions. Even small changes, such as the back button icon, can be configured to be one way for an iOS app and another way for an Android app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Automatic History Magic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to all the configuration that can be done with &lt;code&gt;$ionicConfigProvider&lt;/code&gt;, we&amp;#39;ve also added &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/docs/api/service/$ionicHistory/&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ionicHistory&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which includes functionality that was available in previous versions of Ionic, but wraps them in an Angular service and adds new features. &lt;code&gt;$ionicHistory&lt;/code&gt; keeps track of an app&amp;#39;s views and history stack as the user navigates. Similar to the way a browser behaves, an Ionic app is able to keep track of the previous view, the current view, and the forward view (if there is one).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, a typical web browser only keeps track of one history stack in a linear fashion. Ionic&amp;#39;s &lt;code&gt;$ionicHistory&lt;/code&gt; is able to keep track of multiple histories and follow the user as he or she navigates among different views and different histories. For example, an app with tabs has its own history stack for each tab, so a user can navigate a few views in Tab A, then navigate a few in Tab B, and return to Tab A, with the previous stack location having been maintained the whole time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;But Wait, There&amp;#39;s MORE!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have so many things in store for 2015 that we couldn&amp;#39;t resist offering you a little sneak peek...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Here&amp;#39;s What&amp;#39;s Next!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chromium builds for Android: We&amp;#39;ll be integrating Chromium builds into the CLI soon, but remember that &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.nraboy.com/2014/10/use-crosswalk-ionic-framework-android-apps/&quot;&gt;you can do this now with Crosswalk&lt;/a&gt;. What this means for you is drastically improved performance on Android devices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that view elements are cached in the DOM, we&amp;#39;ll be adding the &amp;quot;swipe to go back&amp;quot; feature between pages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since Android provides the necessary scroll events, we&amp;#39;ll be refactoring our scrolling, such that we can remove JS scrolling on Android devices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is our &lt;em&gt;last Beta release&lt;/em&gt;! Once “swipe to go back” and removal of JS scrolling on Android updates are added, we&amp;#39;re going to call Ionic v1.0 feature complete and roll out the Release Candidate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our new navigation and transition system provides a lot more power for animations. In the near future, we&amp;#39;ll be creating an animations pack that can easily extend Ionic&amp;#39;s animations and allow apps to do some pretty slick stuff with very minimal code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;More Ionicons! We will be adding to and improving our &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicons.com/&quot;&gt;beloved font icon pack&lt;/a&gt; to pair nicely with the next Ionic release. Spinning font icons will be removed in lieu of a special new loading spinner project we&amp;#39;re working on…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh, and let&amp;#39;s not forget &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionic.io&quot;&gt;Ionic.io&lt;/a&gt;, which will give all Ionic developers access to powerful services like Analytics, A/B testing, and live-updating of apps without app store submission. Sign up on the alpha list for more info as we move closer to release!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Setting the Bar for Maximum Awesomeness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We encourage the Ionic community to check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md&quot;&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt; for this release, review our &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/docs/&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;, and read up on all the new APIs. Ionic has evolved into a full-fledged SDK for mobile apps, and we believe the updates we&amp;#39;ve made in this release will make app development an even more enjoyable process for all of you. Thanks to all our community members who have provided feedback and improvements to the open source project. We are very grateful to you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Docs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/docs/api/directive/ionView/&quot;&gt;View LifeCycle and Events&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/docs/api/directive/ionNavView/&quot;&gt;Navigation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/docs/api/provider/$ionicConfigProvider/&quot;&gt;Ionic Config&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md&quot;&gt;Ionic Changelog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.angularjs.org/guide/migration#migrating-from-1-2-to-1-3&quot;&gt;Angular v1.2 to v1.3 Migration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ojMy6m_fcxc&quot;&gt;Angular v1.3 (ngEurope 2014)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 02:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/the-final-beta/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/the-final-beta/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome Josh Bavari to the Ionic Team</title>
        <description>&lt;div style=&quot;height: 360px; width: 360px; border-radius: 600px; border: 6px solid #4e8ef7; overflow: hidden; margin: 5px auto 40px;&quot;&gt; 
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/josh-bavari.png&quot; alt=&quot;Josh Bavari&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m really excited to introduce Josh Bavari (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jbavari&quot;&gt;@jbavari&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter, &lt;a href=&quot;http://forum.ionicframework.com/users/jbavari/activity&quot;&gt;@jbavari&lt;/a&gt; on the Forum, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jbavari&quot;&gt;jbavari&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub) as our newest Ionic team member!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Josh has spent the last few years working on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://cordova.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Cordova&lt;/a&gt; open source project. Starting with version 1.9, he&amp;#39;s followed the project from its earlier days and actively contributes to it, helping maintain the &lt;a href=&quot;http://plugins.cordova.io/&quot;&gt;Cordova Plugin Registry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Josh has been playing with technology and developing software since his childhood. Since joining the professional field in 2007, he&amp;#39;s been a part of development projects for start-ups, small to medium-sized businesses, and enterprise companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Josh&amp;#39;s passions are developing, helping others by speaking and presenting, and contributing to open source projects, which led him to discover that working on Ionic is his professional calling, lining up with his purpose in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his free time, Josh trains in the gentle art of jiu-jitsu, hikes and bikes challenging trails, snowboards, tastes many of the finer Rockies beers, and hacks on code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect to see some awesome things from Josh. He joins the team remotely, out of beautiful Boulder, CO, to help strengthen the Ionic CLI tooling, integrate additional browsers and conveniences for Ionic developers, help community members, and help with some of the other back-end integration pieces that help strengthen Ionic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the team, Josh!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 04:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/welcome-josh/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/welcome-josh/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing Ionic Lab</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;showcase-image&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/ionic-lab-header.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just added a new feature to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/getting-started&quot;&gt;Ionic CLI&lt;/a&gt; tool that we&amp;#39;re calling &lt;strong&gt;Ionic Lab&lt;/strong&gt;. Ionic Lab makes it much easier to test your apps on multiple screen sizes and platform types:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/lab.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want Ionic to be both a great SDK and a toolchain that gives hybrid developers a leg up on native, and this is one of our first big steps in that direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started with Ionic Lab, make sure to update to the latest version of Ionic in NPM:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;npm install -g ionic
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve extended the &lt;code&gt;serve&lt;/code&gt; command to open the new Lab UI:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;ionic serve --lab
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;ve used the &lt;code&gt;serve&lt;/code&gt; command before, you&amp;#39;ll feel right at home with this one. Just like &lt;code&gt;serve&lt;/code&gt;, it opens
your app in a browser, but now it shows you what your app will look like on a phone, with both iOS and Android
side by side. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, it supports Live Reload and all the other goodies we&amp;#39;ve added over the last couple of months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoy this new feature. Expect a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; more from Ionic Lab in the near future!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/ionic-lab/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/ionic-lab/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moving Forward with ngCordova</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post by &lt;a href=&quot;http://paolobernasconi.com/&quot;&gt;Paolo Bernasconi&lt;/a&gt;, lead developer on &lt;a href=&quot;http://ngcordova.com/&quot;&gt;ngCordova&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To watch &lt;a href=&quot;http://ngcordova.com/&quot;&gt;ngCordova&lt;/a&gt; grow from a small idea to a popular open source project with over 1250 stars on GitHub has been a great pleasure for me. Since its inception in July 2014, I&amp;#39;ve had the opportunity to learn about creating and maintaining a GitHub repository, and I&amp;#39;ve come to realize the true power of the open source community and individual contributors. With the community&amp;#39;s troubleshooting help and submissions, we&amp;#39;ve been able to improve ngCordova more rapidly and effectively than one person, or even a small team, ever could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first built ngCordova, it covered 14 basic Cordova plugins. Now it has &lt;strong&gt;47&lt;/strong&gt; and counting, ranging from Push Notifications to Facebook support. We have since released 8 versions, received 230 pull requests from 49 contributors, and resolved over 170 issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So, what&amp;#39;s next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first new feature in ngCordova&amp;#39;s future is an automatic &lt;code&gt;deviceready&lt;/code&gt; check to determine whether a device is ready to use plugins. Currently, the only way to ensure this is to manually insert plugin calls inside the event-listener:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;document.addEventListener(&amp;quot;deviceready&amp;quot;, function () {
  $cordovaPlugin.someFunction().then(success, error);
}, false);

// OR with Ionic

$ionicPlatform.ready(function() {
  $cordovaPlugin.someFunction().then(success, error);
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;event check&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; needs to be done for each plugin method, which becomes a bit tedious and over-bloats code in the controller. Soon, ngCordova will call the &lt;code&gt;deviceready&lt;/code&gt; event in the background, making it easier and simpler to use plugins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important feature on the roadmap is an improved demo app. Cordova plugins can often be very hard to use, and there are times when you might have no idea why your app isn&amp;#39;t working or what error is being produced. While the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ng-cordova/tree/master/demo/www/app&quot;&gt;current demo&lt;/a&gt; does include quite a few plugins, we plan to support &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; plugins in ngCordova, with very detailed examples and unit-tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we understand the need for great documentation, so we are improving the docs with more comprehensive methods for each plugin API (&lt;a href=&quot;http://ngcordova.com/docs/#Facebook&quot;&gt;see the Facebook plugin for an example&lt;/a&gt;), so you&amp;#39;ll have all the information you need readily available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What about testing in the browser?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest issues with app development using Cordova plugins is the fact that it can sometimes break an app when testing in the browser, giving us the &amp;quot;white screen of death&amp;quot;. ngCordova does have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ng-cordova/tree/master/src/mocks&quot;&gt;mocks module&lt;/a&gt;, but it requires a lot of extra code in your controller to simulate the phone environment and isn&amp;#39;t well documented at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s why I created a Google Chrome extension called &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/cordova-mocks/iigcccneenmnplhhfhaeahiofeeeifpn&quot;&gt;Cordova Mocks&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pbernasconi/chrome-cordova&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;), which generates mock-data and automatically injects it into your browser. It follows the same API that Cordova plugins use, so the only thing you have to do is install the extension and start using your app as if you were testing on your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It currently supports the following plugins, with many more to come:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camera&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device Motion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device Orientation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dialogs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flashlight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geolocation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Globalization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network Information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, you&amp;#39;ll be able to configure the data yourself in an options panel built into the extension. Also, expect a Firefox (and maybe Safari) extension in the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ngCordova is still growing day by day and always welcomes new ideas and plugins. If you encounter any issues or want to get official support for a specific plugin, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ng-cordova/issues/new&quot;&gt;create a new issue&lt;/a&gt;, and stay tuned for new features and fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 11:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/moving-forward-with-ngcordova/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/moving-forward-with-ngcordova/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OAuth with Ionic and ngCordova</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a guest post by &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.nraboy.com/&quot;&gt;Nic Raboy&lt;/a&gt;, an application developer with a strong background in Android, AngularJS, Ionic, Java, SQL, and Unity3D. Nic writes often about Ionic and how to build great hybrid apps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get a lot of inquiries regarding OAuth 2.0 with Apache Cordova and Ionic Framework applications. Although I do have &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.nraboy.com/2014/07/using-oauth-2-0-service-ionicframework/&quot;&gt;another post&lt;/a&gt; elaborating on how to accomplish this, I decided to take it a step further and make a simplistic library for AngularJS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nraboy/ng-cordova-oauth&quot;&gt;ngCordovaOauth&lt;/a&gt;, which can be found on GitHub. It was designed to make it as simple as possible to obtain access tokens for some of the popular web APIs, such as Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took my ngCordovaOauth library a step further, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://ngcordova.com/docs/#Oauth&quot;&gt;included it&lt;/a&gt; in the official &lt;a href=&quot;http://ngcordova.com/&quot;&gt;ngCordova&lt;/a&gt; project. For the sake of this tutorial, I&amp;#39;m going to explain things around the official ngCordova library which is now the official implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was designing the OAuth functionality, my strategy was to expect a promise based on the login flow. If the flow is successful, we will receive an object containing whatever the server responds with. Otherwise, we&amp;#39;ll get some kind of error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I designed this with Ionic Framework in mind, it will also work for any Apache Cordova or Phonegap application that makes use of AngularJS. With this in mind, let&amp;#39;s set up the library for use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;ionic start IonicProject blank
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;IonicProject
ionic platform add android
ionic platform add ios
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that if you are not using a Mac, you cannot build for iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OAuth with ngCordova relies heavily on the Apache Cordova &lt;a href=&quot;http://cordova.apache.org/docs/en/3.0.0/cordova_inappbrowser_inappbrowser.md.html&quot;&gt;InAppBrowser&lt;/a&gt; plugin. If you&amp;#39;d like to know more about how this plugin works, you can view my &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.nraboy.com/2014/07/launch-external-urls-ionicframework/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; on the topic, otherwise just continue by running the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;cordova plugin add https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf/cordova-plugin-inappbrowser.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your Ionic project is now ready for the ngCordova library.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ng-cordova/archive/master.zip&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; it and include &lt;strong&gt;ng-cordova.min.js&lt;/strong&gt; into your &lt;strong&gt;www/js&lt;/strong&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open the &lt;strong&gt;www/index.html&lt;/strong&gt; file and include the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;script &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;src=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;js/ng-cordova.min.js&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more item must be added in order to fully make use of this plugin. You must inject ngCordova into your AngularJS module found in the &lt;strong&gt;www/js/app.js&lt;/strong&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;angular&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;module&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;starter&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;ionic&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;ngCordova&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of how you might use the OAuth with the ngCordova library:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;ionicExample&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;angular&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;module&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;starter&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;ionic&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;ngCordova&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]);&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;ionicExample&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;controller&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;OauthExample&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$scope&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$cordovaOauth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$scope&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;googleLogin&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$cordovaOauth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;google&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;CLIENT_ID_HERE&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;https://www.googleapis.com/auth/urlshortener&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;https://www.googleapis.com/auth/userinfo.email&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;stringify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of right now, the following methods are available:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$cordovaOauth&lt;/span&gt;.dropbox&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;string appKey&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$cordovaOauth&lt;/span&gt;.digitalOcean&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;string clientId, string clientSecret&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$cordovaOauth&lt;/span&gt;.google&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;string clientId, array appScope&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$cordovaOauth&lt;/span&gt;.github&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;string clientId, string clientSecret, array appScope&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$cordovaOauth&lt;/span&gt;.facebook&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;string clientId, array appScope&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$cordovaOauth&lt;/span&gt;.linkedin&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;string clientId, string clientSecret, array appScope, string state&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$cordovaOauth&lt;/span&gt;.instagram&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;string clientId, array appScope&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$cordovaOauth&lt;/span&gt;.box&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;string clientId, string clientSecret, string state&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some things to note about OAuth with ngCordova:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It will only work on your device or simulator. It will not work in the web browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All redirect / callback URIs must point to http://localhost/callback; otherwise, the login flow will not complete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have your access token, you can typically make full use of the web APIs for that service. For example, if you wanted to use one of the Digital Ocean APIs, you might do the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;ionicExample&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;angular&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;module&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;starter&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;ionic&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;ngCordova&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]);&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;ionicExample&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;controller&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;DigitalOceanExample&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$scope&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$http&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$cordovaOauth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$scope&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;digitalOceanLogin&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$cordovaOauth&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;digitalOcean&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;CLIENT_ID_HERE&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;CLIENT_SECRET_HERE&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;localStorage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;setItem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;access_token&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;access_token&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$scope&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;getDroplets&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$http&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;defaults&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;headers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;common&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Authorization&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Bearer &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;localStorage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;getItem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;access_token&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$http&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;https://api.digitalocean.com/v2/droplets&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;success&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;stringify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;droplets&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that in the above example, we are using the access token. In this particular example, the access token is used in the header, but in many APIs, the access token is passed in the POST or GET parameters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding OAuth to your Ionic apps is easy with the new &lt;a href=&quot;http://ngcordova.com/docs/#Oauth&quot;&gt;OAuth support&lt;/a&gt; in ngCordova. With support for such providers as Google, Facebook, and Dropbox, it&amp;#39;s just a matter of adding your authentication tokens and linking with the plugin. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support for Twitter, which uses a slightly different client-side token system, is coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 02:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/oauth-ionic-ngcordova/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/oauth-ionic-ngcordova/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Beyond &quot;Framework&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As the first anniversary of Ionic gets closer, we’ve been reflecting on how things have changed from when &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/adamdbradley&quot;&gt;Adam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/maxlynch&quot;&gt;Max&lt;/a&gt;, and I first got together to build a framework that would make it easier for developers to build beautiful, native-quality hybrid mobile apps using web technologies. At the start, we just wanted to create something that &lt;i&gt;we would want to use&lt;/i&gt; ourselves (as it turned out, we weren’t the only ones!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ionic is almost one year old. As it has grown, at a pace that continues to amaze us, we have expanded the tools and services that go along with it. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic-cli&quot;&gt;Ionic CLI&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/creator/&quot;&gt;Creator&lt;/a&gt; (which has thousands of Beta invitations going out each day!) are two such examples. Ionic has become so much more than an HTML5 mobile development framework. It is a collection of components, animations, gestures, tools, etc., all targeted at enabling people to build compelling mobile apps that rival native apps’ performance and attractiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, we’ve also seen an incredible &lt;a href=&quot;http://forum.ionicframework.com/&quot;&gt;community&lt;/a&gt; form organically alongside us. Projects like &lt;a href=&quot;http://ngcordova.com/&quot;&gt;ngCordova&lt;/a&gt;, an Ionic community effort, continue to grow and evolve. Our new &lt;strong&gt;“ions”&lt;/strong&gt; concept, a way to include new components for Ionic as plugins without adding them into the core, will be gaining more resources over the next few months. And with our roadmap heading quickly towards RC 0 in the coming weeks, we’ll be releasing a brand new page transition and animation system, platform design updates, improved scrolling, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add all of these things up, and suddenly, the term “framework” no longer adequately describes what Ionic truly offers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was once an open source framework is really an open source Software Development Kit that lives inside the greater Ionic ecosystem, which will soon grow to include not only Ionic SDK, the CLI, and Creator, but a &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionic.io/&quot;&gt;suite of backend tools and services&lt;/a&gt; that integrate seemlessly with the SDK to allow developers and businesses to build, deploy, and manage highly complex mobile apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those tools and services will eventually include products like analytics, A/B testing, and live updating, to name just a few. Many of you have asked how we plan to fund our continued work on Ionic, and if you’re familiar with our &lt;a href=&quot;http://codiqa.com/&quot;&gt;past&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://jetstrap.com&quot;&gt;products&lt;/a&gt;, then you know how we have done things: keep our open source project free and charge for optional backend services and tools that integrate into it. The complete suite of Ionic services will allow us grow our business, and in turn, enable us to keep the SDK and Creator free for anyone in the world to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The open source SDK will always be the core of Ionic, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://drifty.com&quot;&gt;Drifty&lt;/a&gt; will always support it. It’s a priority for us because it enables anyone in the world to access and use the code, which lowers the barrier to entry to mobile development for web developers, career-changing professionals, and members of groups currently underrepresented in tech. We hope that by giving the world Ionic, we will collectively change the future of mobile development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 02:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/beyond-framework/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/beyond-framework/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tinder for X with Ionic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When we released the &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/driftyco/ionic-contrib-swipe-cards&quot;&gt;Swipe Cards&lt;/a&gt; ion (our term for Ionic add-ons/widgets), Tinder wasn&amp;#39;t really on our radar. At the time, we were impressed by some of the unique UX elements in the app &lt;a href=&quot;http://jelly.co/&quot;&gt;Jellyfish&lt;/a&gt; and wanted to prove they could be built just as well in Ionic and with the power of HTML5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the #1 request we&amp;#39;ve had since the release was support for Tinder-style swipe cards. While we can&amp;#39;t say whether or not we have any experience with Tinder, we do love the way Tinder makes it easy to process a large list of items, indicating a positive or negative reaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s amazing how broadly applicable the swipe card interface is, and this &amp;quot;Tinder for X&amp;quot; phenomenon was something we wanted to help Ionic developers jump on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we are happy to release the Ionic Tinder-style Cards ion. This ion has support for swiping cards left and right, and also animating the stack of cards underneath
the current card. Try it out below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 70px; width: 320px&quot;&gt;
   &lt;p data-height=&quot;568&quot; data-width=&quot;320&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;3572&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;nxEdH&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;ionic&quot; class=&#39;codepen&#39;&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&#39;http://codepen.io/ionic/pen/nxEdH/&#39;&gt;Ionic Ion: Tinder Cards&lt;/a&gt; by Ionic (&lt;a href=&#39;http://codepen.io/ionic&#39;&gt;@ionic&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&#39;http://codepen.io&#39;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;script async src=&quot;//codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also marks the first usage of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/collide&quot;&gt;collide&lt;/a&gt; animation library for support for physics-style animations like springs and gravity. Notice how if you drag too little and let go, the cards spring back into place!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Getting started&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started, use bower to add the ion to your project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;bower install ionic-contrib-tinder-cards
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the demo for a full example of how to use this ion: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic-contrib-tinder-cards/tree/master/demo&quot;&gt;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic-contrib-tinder-cards/tree/master/demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/tinder-for-x/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/tinder-for-x/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Built with Ionic: Songhop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;showcase-image&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/songhop-header.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://songhop.fm/&quot;&gt;Songhop&lt;/a&gt;, a super fast way to find new music, streams music that can be quickly flipped through using swipe gestures to interact with the Tinder-esque interface. The team behind &lt;a href=&quot;https://thinkster.io/&quot;&gt;Thinkster.io&lt;/a&gt;: Eric Simons, Albert Pai, and Matt Green, built the app, which is targeted at teens and young adults. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: right; margin-right: -160px; margin-bottom: 80px; width: 50%;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/img/blog/songhop-preview-right.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/songhop-preview-right.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In early 2013, Simons, Pai, and Green wrote what is now the de facto tutorial on AngularJS and have since taught over 500K developers AngularJS. They originally heard about Ionic from the AngularJS community and agreed that it would take significantly more time to learn native languages than to learn how Ionic was set up. They built the entire Songhop app on top of Ionic’s UI elements and plugins: modals, dialogs, navigation controllers, swipe gestures, etc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left; margin-left: -120px; margin-right: 40px; margin-bottom: 70px; width: 32%;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/img/blog/songhop-preview-left.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/songhop-preview-left.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We custom-skinned a lot of components, and it was unbelievably easy to do so,” says Simons. “The framework is absolutely fantastic, and the documentation and resources that Ionic provides is unreal. I’ve honestly never seen such comprehensive docs and resources for a framework or platform. Further, the design decisions that the Ionic team has made are very intuitive and straightforward, which makes it a lot easier to understand how things work.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simons debunks the myth of “native speed apps,” saying, “We have had precisely 0 users (out of thousands) complain about our app being slow, buggy, etc, so the supposed benefit of having ’native speed’ apps just isn’t true anymore.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Songhop is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/songhop/id899245239?mt=8&quot;&gt;iOS App Store&lt;/a&gt;, and Simons and his team have plans to teach users to make their own versions of Songhop in an upcoming &lt;a href=&quot;https://thinkster.io/IonicTutorial&quot;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/built-with-ionic-songhop/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/built-with-ionic-songhop/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dreamforce Hackathon Powerups!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;showcase-image&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/dreamforce-ionic-header.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.salesforce.com/million-dollar-hackathon&quot;&gt;Dreamforce 2014 Hackathon&lt;/a&gt; right around the corner, we wanted to share some great resources from Ionic, Salesforce, and Heroku, to make sure you don&amp;#39;t waste any time getting to work building your great app and sharing in that wonderful $1M!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;re attending Dreamforce, please visit the Ionic booth in the DevZone. We&amp;#39;ll be debuting Creator and demonstrating new ways to build hybrid apps using Ionic. We look forward to seeing you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Heroku Mobile App Template&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Heroku team put together a great &lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.heroku.com/blogs/2014-10-02-heroku-mobile-app-template&quot;&gt;starting template&lt;/a&gt; for building an app with Ionic, Angular, Cordova, and NodeJS on Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is your best bet to get a great app up and running, complete with a backend and frontend. You can even add support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/heroku/mobile-template1#accessing-forcecom&quot;&gt;force.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why Ionic?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think Ionic is the best bet for Dreamforce participants to build their apps faster, with fewer headaches. Instead of having to configure and build two complicated native apps, you can build one cross-platform app with web technologies you already know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By using Ionic you can get started building the parts of the app that are actually unique. That could be the difference between shipping a great app at the end of the hackathon or being stuck in the weeds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you there, and good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/dreamforce-hackathon-resources/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/dreamforce-hackathon-resources/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using Ionic and Heroku</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;showcase-image&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/heroku-ionic-header.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve noticed a lot of Ionic developers using Heroku side-by-side, either as a backend or to actually host their Ionic app as a mobile website or externally-loaded app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help with that, we&amp;#39;ve built a ready-to-go &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic-heroku-button&quot;&gt;Ionic app&lt;/a&gt; with Node.js and Express, to either host your Ionic app as a mobile website,
or to build a Node.js API server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started, all you need to do is click the Heroku Deploy button below, or see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic-heroku-button&quot;&gt;manual instructions&lt;/a&gt; on the github repo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://heroku.com/deploy?template=https://github.com/driftyco/ionic-heroku-button&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.herokucdn.com/deploy/button.png&quot; alt=&quot;Deploy&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope this helps you get up and running with Ionic and a great backend like Heroku. Give it a spin, and let us know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/heroku-ionic/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/heroku-ionic/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Built with Ionic: Mallzee</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;showcase-image&quot; src=&quot;/img/blog/mallzee-header.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mallzee.com/&quot;&gt;Mallzee&lt;/a&gt;, “the personal stylist in your pocket,” pulls together over two million products from 100 big-name fashion brands to find must-have clothes suited to its users, who are primarily 16-35 year-olds who love fashion but are too busy to spend a lot of time shopping. Mallzee’s unique Style Feeds allow users to get search-specific, receive price drop alerts, and be inspired by top fashion bloggers and personal stylists. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mallzee CTO &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wedgybo&quot;&gt;Jamie Sutherland&lt;/a&gt; heard about Ionic when it was being promoted on AngularJS lists. “We were building an app with the same sort of ethos,” says Sutherland. “We wanted to create reusable components, so we could make our next apps quicker. When we heard about Ionic, we were keen to take a look, and we weren’t disappointed!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: right; margin-right: -160px; width: 50%;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/img/blog/mallzee-preview-right.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/mallzee-preview-right.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the company had already published the first version of the Mallzee app. In May 2014, the team decided to replace their existing UI work with Ionic, which was approaching a 1.0.0 version. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We figured thousands of eyes on the code is better than a few, so it would pay off in the long run,” says Sutherland. “So far, we’ve been right.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sutherland says Ionic helped streamline app development by reducing the amount of work needed to make a high-quality hybrid application. “It takes away the pain of having to create a lot of the standard components people expect and know how to use in their native counterparts,” he says. “Because we’d already created similar components, we were able to quickly switch out old for new in the space of a few weeks! In the end, we’ve used almost the entire framework. We even have a few components waiting to give back!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left; margin-left: -120px; margin-right: 40px; width: 32%;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/img/blog/mallzee-preview-left.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/mallzee-preview-left.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sutherland adds, “Being invested in AngularJS, I love the simplicity of fitting together components to create great-looking apps in no time at all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the Mallzee team used Ionic to create a whole interface purely from markup, the marketing group is able to edit sections of the app without help from the development team. “They control the inspiration section of the app, without having to have an in-depth knowledge of coding,” says Sutherland. “Basic HTML skills are enough for them to produce great results.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mallzee originally chose hybrid over native because they were all web developers. “We’d looked at great PhoneGap apps (Twist, Untappd) and figured we could do something like that,” says Sutherland. “We’d no idea how hard it would be, especially when you are rolling most of the components yourself, as all the frameworks at the time (jQuery Mobile, Sencha Touch) were too heavy. Although we only support iPhone at the moment, another factor in our decision was cross-platform support. We focused on the iOS platform first, to get the user experience nailed there before covering others. It should be a simple process, and now we’re ready to tackle that and roll out Android before the end of the year.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download Mallzee from Apple&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/mallzee/id681106862&quot;&gt;iOS App Store&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 11:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/built-with-ionic-mallzee/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/built-with-ionic-mallzee/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Refreshing our Pull-to-Refresh</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For a while now, we’ve wanted to update Pull To Refresh in Ionic. It worked, but it wasn’t exciting, and since it’s a goal of ours at Ionic to make every component as enjoyable to use as it can be, we decided it was time for a change. Here&amp;#39;s some of the lessons in semiotics and UX that we learned...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wanting to make it fun and playful, we started by binding the rotation of the arrow icon to how far you pull down the view. It was fun. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/benjsperry&quot;&gt;Ben&lt;/a&gt; and I spent a good ten minutes each just playing with pulling the view down. We quickly realized a problem, though: While it was fun, it was not practical. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most users don’t sit and play with the pull to refresh animation on their phones; they “use” their phones. They “use” pull to refresh to get the information they want, and they want it now. That means they swipe up quickly and expect the pull to refresh to trigger and update. They swipe so fast, the animation doesn’t even happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: right; margin-right: -160px&quot;&gt;
  
 &lt;div class=&quot;phone-case&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p data-height=&quot;568&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;3572&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;nqIrC&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; class=&#39;codepen&#39;&gt;See the Pen by &lt;a href=&#39;http://codepen.io/ionic/pen/nqIrC&#39;&gt;Ionic&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#39;http://codepen.io/ionic&#39;&gt;@ionic&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&#39;http://codepen.io&#39;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;script async src=&quot;//codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we went back to a regular fixed-time animation, updated the default icons to be something more visually appealing, and moved on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing we noticed was that most API calls are pretty fast, perhaps too fast. Our refresher would return to the home position as soon as it was told the information requested was received. This meant that as soon as you let go of the refresher when swiping up, it wouldn’t spin; instead, it would return immediately to the home position. We have an internal Hacker News app we were using to test this (more info on that soon). The front page of Hacker News doesn’t update every five seconds, so most of the time, a refresh does nothing. We were left unsure if an update actually fired. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up console logs allows developers to make sure the refresh actually happened. Users don’t get the reassurance of a console log, though, so your UI must be reassuring enough on its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to force 400ms of the refreshing spinner animation. If the data came back sooner, we’d still apply it immediately, but we’d show the spinner for a bit, so the user would know a refresh had happened. To a developer, this may feel misleading. The refresh is already complete, so why are we still showing the animation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users don’t care about what’s going on under the hood.&lt;/strong&gt; A big part of UX is keeping a user in familiar territory and reassuring him or her that the app is working properly. The user’s confidence that the refresh happened trumps its technical representation. In our updated pull to refresh, if an update takes longer than 400ms, it will continue to spin until the data is available. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think you’ll agree, the end result is a pull to refresh that’s enjoyable to use and communicates its function clearly. I really enjoyed going into this level of critical thinking on just one component. It’s a standard to which I’m proud to say we hold ourselves with every new Ionic feature. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out what we did &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/driftyco/ionic/commit/db27fb116cd3139b271cf9d20c462fb3746f25df&quot;&gt;under the hood on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, or take a look at how to add it into your app from our &lt;a href=&quot;http://ionicframework.com/docs/api/directive/ionRefresher/&quot;&gt;Docs&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 03:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ionicframework.com/blog/refreshing-pull-to-refresh/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ionicframework.com/blog/refreshing-pull-to-refresh/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
